Indrajeet Pandit





Pune , Maharashtra +91.9764500040

indrapandit48@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/i ndrajeet-pandit-a8266b40/

III SKILLS

- Global Sourcing
- e-Sourcing
- Negotiation
- Project procurement
- Team management & leadership
- Expedition
- New vendor development
- Tactical purchasing
- · Strategic sourcing
- Low cost country sourcing
- Multicultural experience

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

SAP

Oracle

Microsoft AX

SCM STAR

SIENEREX

MS Office

@ LANGUAGES

Marathi

Hindi

English

Project Procurement Manager

PROFILE • ABOUT ME

Effective and forward-thinking Procurement Manager, bringing forth valuable 08+ years of industry experience, and the skills to achieve real results. Adept in developing key relationships with strategic partners, and committed to working to ensure a company continually moves in the right direction.

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering, Bachelor of Engineering / Bachelor of **Technology**

Dr. D. Y. Patil college of engineering, Akurdi Pune University Pune, Maharashtra

> Graduated May 2012

Sep 2019

- Current

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deputy Manager - Supply chain

Siemens Energy

Pune, Maharashtra

• Industry type - Oil & Gas / Business - Project / Commodities - MBOs, Gas Seal Panels, Lube Oil System etcs

- Responsible to manage team of 03 people & to ensure the plans, organizes and manages the procurement process for all projects
- Managing diverse procurement activities and aligning with design engineering & project management team
- Develop and maintain productive relationships with direct reports, senior management, vendors, other support groups and project team members
- Ensuring accuracy and adequacy of purchasing/contracts negotiation and supply chain administration activities
- Negotiation of T&C, Prices and Vendor Management
- Coordination with expediting and project management teams during project execution to maintain on-time material delivery
- Implementing eSourcing platforms for digital negotiations (eAuctions, eBiddings etcs)

Associate Manager - Materials

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

Kirloskar Brothers Itd

Pune, Maharashtra

• Industry type - Pump / Business - Batch Production / Commodities -Mechanical pump seals

- Procurement of required materials as per the design and quality specifications
- · Coordination with planning team & project stores to ensure availability of required materials
- To arrange top-up quantities in short time frame to meet project requirements / urgencies

O PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birthday 11/10/1990

Gender

Male

Marital Status

Married

Nationality

Indian

• End to end monitoring and control of orders, including expediting, interaction for inspection, close out of purchase order

Purchase Executive - Supply chain

Aug 2016 - Jun 2018

Ateliers François compressors India Ltd

Pune, Maharashtra

- Industry type Compressors / Business Low Batch Production / Commodities - Castings & machined components
- Responsible for procurement of raw material mainly casting and machined part items generated by MRP
- Responsible for identifying & developing alternate vendors for imported items with low cost & right quality
- Developing long term relationship with vendors and managing day to day supply chain performance to ensure meeting of service, cost, delivery and quality norms

Buyer - Supply chain

Oct 2014

Dresser-Rand India pvt Itd

- Jul 2016

Pune, Maharashtra

- Industry type Oil & Gas compressors / Business After market spares / Commodities - All compressor components
- Source competitive bids from qualified suppliers and negotiates with suppliers over cost and delivery
- Prepare and issue purchase orders and enquiries to suppliers

Graduate Engineering Trainee - Procurement

Sep 2013

Emerson Electric co.

- Sep 2014

Pune. Maharashtra

- Industry type HVAC compressors / Business Mass production / Commodities - Castings & machined components
- Work closely with the Vendors, Purchasing Manager, Buyers, Planning & Warehouse team to ensure timely availability of required material on time with good quality

| P. | DECLARATION |
|----|-------------|
|----|-------------|

I, Indrajeet Pandit, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Indrajeet Pandit

Pune, Maharashtra 17/04/2021